[Music]
Welcome to this business central launch
event about what's new in ALGO for
GitHub on security. My name is Freddy
Christensen, technical evangelist out of
Microsoft and I have with me, thank you
Freddie. My name is Maria Jilelesa and I
also work on Ago for GitHub with Freddy
and we'll jump right into the agenda
here and talk about deprecations.
While talking about deprecations is kind
of like talking about what's not new,
right? But um it's actually not about so
much about what's deprecated. It's more
about having a website now where we are
explaining what's going to be deprecated
in the future. So there are some changes
in effect that will like stop working
after October 1st this year and you'll
find those here. You'll also get
warnings in the build if you're using
these features. So consult this site
AKMS algo deprecations to see what's
being deprecated in the near future.
Beside that there is also a AKMS link
called AKMS algo release notes. Clicking
at this one will take you to the release
notes. Well, no
wonder version 6.4 just released and the
topmost release notes is from version
6.4. If you'll find like features
described on top of version 6.4, they
will not be included in version 6.4,
meaning that you probably have to run
preview or yeah or or or they are not
even in preview yet. But you can yeah,
you can ask us that on on GitHub if you
are in doubt. But if they're not
underneath a version number here in the
release notes, they haven't been
released yet in a in a full version. Um,
so next up talking about Azure trusted
signing. Maria, take it away. Hi
everybody. Uh, I'm going to walk you
through what Asia trusted signing is and
how Ago is integrated with it. Um just
the the key takeaway for Azure trusted
signing is that it's the natural
evolution of the signing process which
completely eliminates the need to
manually rotate certificates as well as
storing secrets to access these
certificates. It is a service that Azure
provides. So we get to have the natural
experience and there is also link to the
official documentation that where you
can read more about it. Now off to the
steps on how to set it up with a go. Uh
first and foremost you need to create
the service on Azure which is called
Azure trusted signing account. Uh then
you need to perform an identity
validation and this is the hardest step
of the process where you need to uh
verify indeed that you are who you say
you are and because there's going to be
like certificates is issued on your name
and uh it needs to be made sure that
this is the right identity for it. Once
you have at least one identity
validation uh request completed uh you
can create a certificate profile where
you will be able to create certificates
for your signing purpose for your
signing um purposes. Uh after that you
need to make the connection to to GitHub
and the first step is to create a
managed identity. The needed uh role or
permission for that is trusted signing
certificate profile signer and creating
federated credentials is where you uh
completely make the link to GitHub. Uh
on ago sites you only need to create a
secret Azure credentials which you might
already have because it's also used for
integrating with other Azure uh services
such as key votes. And lastly, you need
to create a trusted signing setting for
your GitHub repository which looks like
this. It has an endpoint account and
certificate profile. Uh setting up this
will make the signing process seamless
throughout uh all your GitHub repository
that utilize this feature.
Next up is GitHub app authentication.
So let me explain quickly what that is.
As you know, you have we we require you
to create a personal access token or a
secret that contains a personal access
token. In the beginning, we had the
classic personal access tokens that like
impersonate a user have same access to
all repositors and organizations that
the user have uh and are used to
authenticate to the APIs and so forth
and and that's really a security wise
it's a problem. So we created the fine
grained personal access token. It still
impersonates a user and but it's now
scoped to one organization and a select
repositories. Still imposes some
security risk if exposed to uh to to an
evil person or whatever. Uh what we have
now is GitHub app authentication. And
how why does that differentiate? What
you have now in your secret is not the
actual access token. In your secret, you
have an app ID and a private key. And
that combination is used to create a
short-lived access token. And the only
thing that ever leaves the the GitHub
runner is the shortlived access token
that's typically living for an hour. Um,
and and with that, you can only do the
stuff that this access token was created
for. So if we create an access token for
reading a repository, that's what you
can do with that access token if it ever
gets
exposed. Again here there's no
impersonation. Uh it's a bot or it's a
automation. Um it's it's the app. Um,
and it's scoped to one organization and
a select repositories and and you can do
exactly you can get the permissions for
the access token that the app is set up
to be able to give you. There's one
scenario that doesn't work. That's
GitHub packages. So, uh, that's a
feature that GitHub is is is missing. Uh
what you can do there is you can create
a specific personal access token that
only has uh packages readr and nothing
else. That would actually uh yeah that
would solve that problem. But let's have
a look at the GitHub app authentication
and see how that actually looks. There's
a number of uh runs here. And if we look
at this one, the very first update algo
system files I ran manually run by
Freddy DK and the um the the commit that
resolved from that uh workflow run the
update elgo system files here is a
commit pushed by Freddy DK. So that is
done by my personal access token. That's
my user that that was running this one
and it was my user that pushed this one.
So that was done by GH token workflow
that was uh impersonating me. The next
one I ran here is done manually run by
Freddy DK but the subsequent commit here
is pushed by algo authentication and
that's a bot that is the GitHub app.
Let's have a look at this one which
actually ran this workflow.
um and click
here look into the update elgo system
files and what happens here is that it
gets the app info and it gets a token
response and saying I want access to
this repository and I want the
permissions to read read and read uh
these different things and when I then
discover that yes we have to actually
update the system files then later on
we're going to get a new new
token which is for write write read and
write in order to update or create the
pull request that updates our algo
system files in this repository. So at
any time the access token that we use
does not have more permissions that it
actually than it actually needs to
have. So let's go back to this one and
talk about embed secrets in install apps
and install test apps. We had a workshop
with a partner that was using algo or
was in
uh in the process of setting up algo for
their repositories. And one of the
things they told us was that they had
like right there in source code pointers
to
um to blobs that were like in a secure
storage area, meaning there was like a
SAS token there in clear text. Um well,
it might be a read token. it might not
actually be uh a problem but we decided
that that that should not happen. We
should not have secrets in clear text.
So what we did was we added a feature
that enables you to instead of having an
install apps where you have like oh this
is Dropbox but anyway uh where you have
an RL key or whatever now you can
actually have a secret name right there
in your install apps that allows you to
store the SAS token or the RL key or the
entire URL um away in a secret so that
you never see that one in your logs or
anything like that. Let's just have a
quick look at how that
looks. This
one. Looking at the build here, we'll
see that
uh looking at the parameters, it should
have a list of install apps, which is
just some stars because it's a secret.
Later on, we'll be able to see that when
it's installing the apps, it's actually
installing the Bing Maps app here, but
we cannot see where it came from because
the URL was a secret, obviously. So,
with
that, back to Maria. Thank you, Freddy.
The last section of this presentation is
about running AOG Go for GitHub on
multiple branches. Now, one of the
things we recommend people do when they
use AOG Go is to always use the latest
version or to run updates um uh as soon
as they're available. Now, um uh we
highly recommend that, but we also know
that it's the workflow itself can can
only be run uh one branch at a time. And
with the latest version 6.4, 4 we
actually added the capability to do that
to update Ago system files on multiple
branches at a time. Uh what we also
recommend is to run a go or update AGO
system files on a schedule and we also
acknowledge that there is a limitation
on GitHub that doesn't allow you to do
that for multiple branches that are not
the default branch. So that's why we
added a new setting uh called workflow
schedule where you can define your
chrome schedule as well as list of
branches to include when running the
workflow. Now uh off to a short demo
where I'm going to demonstrate uh
quickly when you update uh a go system
files. There is a new field where you
can specify a list of branches to
update. Um you can use wild cards and
you can use as many branches as the
input allows you. Uh I'm not going to
wait for this to to to to finish. I'm
just going to show you what the result
is. Um you can verify on on the
repository that there are indeed like
two branches that match these uh
patterns and the workflow runs on both
of
them. With that, thanks for watching the
video and see you next time.
Thank you.